Franklyn L. Broomfield

Silver Spring, MD 20905 | (818) 730-5094 | franklynbroomfield@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Experienced strong management skills in the audio-visual field with equally strong leadership skills in the media industry, media event planning, and entertainment productions support fields. I thrive in working in a high-stress environment while multi-tasking. I have a proven history of providing high-level customer service, and I can work effectively with many levels of personnel, vendors, and customers.

EXPERIENCE

PARADISE PRODUCTIONS GROUP, Glendale, CA, 1983 - Present

Sound Engineer and Event Planner

- Operate a variety of sound equipment in and for various churches, events, community concerts, conventions and shows
- Design audio, video, lighting, and media systems for Houses of Worship
- Consult with various venues, churches, and shows to design sound, lights, and media systems
- Edit live programs and services for radio broadcasts
- Conduct seminars for sound and multi-media presentations for clergy, music personnel, and apprentices for House of Worship
- Plan all aspects of events for various organizations ranging from small groups to groups of 6000+. Included but not limited to, housing, catering, media, and A/V

DIAMOND IN THE RAW FOUNDATION, Los Angeles, CA, 2009 - 2022

Production Manager, Stage Manager, Technical Director, and Location Manager

- Supported and created the technical infrastructure for, audio, video, lights, media, communication tools, staging, and the set, for large-scale productions and Award Shows
- Collaborated with the creative team to provide advice regarding the technical needs of the Producer's vision for the show
- Scheduled and conducted Tech rehearsals, and managed the Stage Managers
- As Technical Director, negotiated, scheduled, ordered, and created all the technical infrastructure for the show, including acquiring and managing the show's production crew
- Responsible for identifying and contracting venues for the Opening Reception, Safety Seminar Day, Demonstration Day, Movement Capture Day event, and the Action Icon Award Show. Served as the liaison for the four different venues for the week's events

CLS WORLDWIDE/EMPIRETRANSPORTATION, INC., El Segundo, CA, 1998 - 2007 Local Affiliate Manager, Billing, and Driver Payroll

- Responsible for the administration and compliance of the Local and Worldwide Affiliates
- Negotiated terms, created, and enforced policies, and maintained quality control, customer service standards, resolved customer service and payroll issues
- Established new accounts
- Invoiced hotel billings researched and resolved billing and hotel customer service issues

Special Event Coordinator

- Created and managed the logistical infrastructure for the events
- Organized and managed Security, Chauffeurs, private aircraft, and other assets for the Red Carpet operation of all Premieres, special events, and all of the major Award Shows, such as the Grammy's, Oscars, Emmys, Golden Globes, American Music Awards, Soul Train, Stellar, Spirit, People's Choice Awards, NAACP Image, ESPY, Teen Choice Awards.
- Global Affiliate Network Manager
- Recruited, negotiated terms, services and administrated the vendors and providers for our Worldwide Affiliate Network of Chauffeurs, Security Details, private aircraft for heads of States and VIP's
- Maintained all Affiliates' insurance, government, and municipal compliance information
- Liaison to Corporate Attorney

Accounts Receivable Clerk

- Researched and adjusted all billing issues with customers and converted currency
- Researched and adjusted employee pay issues
- Performed end-of-month closing and generated numerous daily and monthly reports

Employee Relations Manager

- Interviewed, trained, and scheduled personal security agents, chauffeurs, and bus drivers
- Assigned to VIP, government Royal Families, dignitaries, and high-security details

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

President, SCC YOUTH FEDERATION, Los Angeles, CA, 1989 - 2000

- Created a youth organization to support and train Pastors and lay leaders on how to attract and support youth and develop their youth ministries
- Planned various conference events for youth and young adults
- Served as liaison for convention centers, visitors & convention bureaus
- Collaborated with nationwide leaders to plan and develop viable youth programming
- Advised Youth Directors as a Conference Youth Advisory Council member in planning events, camp, and retreat programs

SKILLS

Production & Stage Management
Technical Direction
Customer Service
Catering and Hospitality Training
A/V and Multimedia Production

Public Speaking
Contract Negotiation
Vendor Vetting
Event Planning
Microsoft Office
Team Building

EDUCATION

Howard Community College, Columbia, MD; Entertainment, Audio Visual, Hospitality, Hotel and Convention Management, 2020 to present

Citrus College, Glendora, CA; Theater Arts and Recording Engineer, 2005-2007 Oakwood College, Huntsville, AL; Theology and Business, 1983-1986